Most AI decision tools give a team one confident answer.
Dissent Garden keeps the disagreement you cannot afford to
lose, binds every claim to supplied evidence, and turns
uncertainty into the next reversible test.
Here is a product choice: launch a new onboarding flow to
everyone, or stage it at ten percent.
The evidence includes an activation lift, an unexplained
Android crash regression, no weekend support, successful
rollback drills, and a flexible campaign.
Each fact has a stable evidence ID.
Codex helped build and verify the complete product: contracts,
interface, failure boundaries, browser quality assurance, and
seventeen automated tests.
At runtime, GPT-5.
6 Sol runs Builder, Breaker, and Grounder in isolation and in
parallel.
A fourth GPT-5.
6 pass adjudicates only after all three are complete.
The result is not a vote.
Dissent Garden recommends a ten percent Monday stage, not a
full Friday release.
It preserves the activation upside while refusing to ignore
the Android reliability regression and the weekend support
gap.
Each seat has a different obligation.
Builder finds the strongest bounded proposal.
Breaker exposes failure modes and displaced cost.
Grounder audits the reasoning against the supplied evidence.
They cannot imitate agreement because they do not see one
another before completing their passes.
The arbiter separates atomic claims into survived, disputed,
and unsupported.
Structured output is not enough by itself, so the server
allowlists every evidence ID and demotes evidence-free
survivor claims.
A persuasive model response cannot silently invent support.
The unresolved tension stays visible instead of being averaged
away.
Then the system names the cheapest reversible test: a staffed
ten percent rollout with an Android stop threshold, a rollback
owner, and a review after five hundred activated users.
Every decision enters a hash-chained append-only ledger.
The live GPT-5.
6 sample used six thousand seven hundred sixty-six tokens and
cost about eleven cents.
Repeating the exact untouched decision then reused its
verified receipt in eighty-four milliseconds, with zero model
calls and all six thousand seven hundred sixty-six tokens
avoided.
Corrections invalidate stale reuse without rewriting history.
Plant a Seed turns one decision into a bounded living watch.
Local checks stay free while evidence is repetitive and
tighten their wake threshold after noise.
Material contradictions wake the seed.
Before model work begins, the system must reserve its worst-
case cost against both the seed's dollar ceiling and the
global token budget.
In this thirty-day simulation, twenty-six checks slept, five
woke, none were false wakes, and no budget was breached.
Dissent Garden is a decision workspace for teams shipping
under uncertainty: disagreement that remains useful, evidence
that stays inspectable, memory that gets tighter, and agents
that must earn the right to spend again.